<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Spirituality on My Test Blog on GH</title><link>https://Spiritual-Entanglement.github.io/testblog/tags/spirituality/</link><description>Recent content in Spirituality on My Test Blog on GH</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:26:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Spiritual-Entanglement.github.io/testblog/tags/spirituality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Real Joy</title><link>https://Spiritual-Entanglement.github.io/testblog/posts/my-true-joy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:26:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://Spiritual-Entanglement.github.io/testblog/posts/my-true-joy/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="my-real-joy"&gt;My Real Joy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My real joy is how my relationship with
God has blossomed over the last few
years. Ever since I started to make a
more concerted effort to know God, He
has responded to my persistent efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did not know it was truly possible
to feel God&amp;rsquo;s presence in my daily life
beyond just intillectual knowledge, but
to truly feel God is around me at all
fimes.&lt;/p&gt;</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="my-real-joy">My Real Joy</h1>
<p>My real joy is how my relationship with
God has blossomed over the last few
years. Ever since I started to make a
more concerted effort to know God, He
has responded to my persistent efforts.</p>
<p>I did not know it was truly possible
to feel God&rsquo;s presence in my daily life
beyond just intillectual knowledge, but
to truly feel God is around me at all
fimes.</p>
<p>From the start it is evident that God
has been slowly guiding my growth and
formation. It seems clear that God is
not demanding I become perfect all at
onee, but we work together to affect
my continval growth and formation. I
only have to be persistent and work the
next task. He is asking me to pay attention to.
It all seems to stew, at least from
my and of the relationship, my willingness
to go to God persistently several times a
day in various ways: formal &amp; informal prayer,
reading, contemplating, and, now, via writing.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Some Sermon Ideas on Spiritual Depth pt 1</title><link>https://Spiritual-Entanglement.github.io/testblog/posts/some-sermon-ideas-on-spiritual-depth-pt1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 17:26:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://Spiritual-Entanglement.github.io/testblog/posts/some-sermon-ideas-on-spiritual-depth-pt1/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="some-sermon-ideas-on-spiritual-depth-pt-1"&gt;Some Sermon Ideas on Spiritual Depth pt 1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Related to Psalm 127&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God must lead the work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work done on our own, under our own willpower, will eventually fail. It will be shown to be ineffective and weak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To what can we compare the Kingdom of God? The individual is like an acre of farmland overgrown with weeds. Their soul is the ground. Their daily life is the fertilizer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="first-person"&gt;First person&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One person gets ready, takes some time off of work, and begins pulling weeds by hand; making use of all kinds of tools and implements. She or he works through the morning into the heat of the day. The work is boring and hard.&lt;/p&gt;</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="some-sermon-ideas-on-spiritual-depth-pt-1">Some Sermon Ideas on Spiritual Depth pt 1</h1>
<p>Related to Psalm 127</p>
<p>God must lead the work.</p>
<p>Work done on our own, under our own willpower, will eventually fail.  It will be shown to be ineffective and weak.</p>
<p>To what can we compare the Kingdom of God?  The individual is like an acre of farmland overgrown with weeds.  Their soul is the ground.  Their daily life is the fertilizer.</p>
<h2 id="first-person">First person</h2>
<p>One person gets ready, takes some time off of work, and begins pulling weeds by hand; making use of all kinds of tools and implements.  She or he works through the morning into the heat of the day.  The work is boring and hard.</p>
<p>Some weeds are uprooted easily, and quickly cast into the fire.</p>
<p>Other weeds are hard to pull, and not all the roots are extracted.  What is pulled is burned and destroyed, but the roots remain and quickly and easily begin to grow back.</p>
<p>Day after day the person must pull weeds, but always has to go over previously cleared ground to pull new weeds that have sprouted on that freshly turned ground. Or worse, they have to work again on old weeds, that still have roots deep in the ground.  Many days these old weeds stay under the surface, but eventually new growth breaks ground and begins to grow back stronger than ever.</p>
<p>After the days work, the person is so tired, they have to strength to invest is good fertilizer.  They settle for filling their mind with junk from all manner of convenient sources.</p>
<h2 id="another-person">Another person</h2>
<p>Another person sees the acre of weeds and is overwhelmed by the amount of work, and not knowing where to start.</p>
<p>After attempting to pull weeds, they eventually see the hopelessness of their efforts.</p>
<p>They begin to consult with the master gardener after the day&rsquo;s work instead of consuming endless entertainments.</p>
<p>The master gardener instructs them each night on where to plant good plants that can withstand the weeds.  He shows them how to attend to the plants each day, so they are properly fertilized and cared for.  Under his guidance the few plants grow strong and begin to crowd out the weeds around them.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>