<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on My Test Blog on GH</title><link>https://Spiritual-Entanglement.github.io/testblog/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on My Test Blog on GH</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:26:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Spiritual-Entanglement.github.io/testblog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Real Joy</title><link>https://Spiritual-Entanglement.github.io/testblog/posts/my-true-joy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:26:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://Spiritual-Entanglement.github.io/testblog/posts/my-true-joy/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="my-real-joy"&gt;My Real Joy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My real joy is how my relationship with
God has blossomed over the last few
years. Ever since I started to make a
more concerted effort to know God, He
has responded to my persistent efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did not know it was truly possible
to feel God&amp;rsquo;s presence in my daily life
beyond just intillectual knowledge, but
to truly feel God is around me at all
fimes.&lt;/p&gt;</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="my-real-joy">My Real Joy</h1>
<p>My real joy is how my relationship with
God has blossomed over the last few
years. Ever since I started to make a
more concerted effort to know God, He
has responded to my persistent efforts.</p>
<p>I did not know it was truly possible
to feel God&rsquo;s presence in my daily life
beyond just intillectual knowledge, but
to truly feel God is around me at all
fimes.</p>
<p>From the start it is evident that God
has been slowly guiding my growth and
formation. It seems clear that God is
not demanding I become perfect all at
onee, but we work together to affect
my continval growth and formation. I
only have to be persistent and work the
next task. He is asking me to pay attention to.
It all seems to stew, at least from
my and of the relationship, my willingness
to go to God persistently several times a
day in various ways: formal &amp; informal prayer,
reading, contemplating, and, now, via writing.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Some Sermon Ideas on Spiritual Depth pt 1</title><link>https://Spiritual-Entanglement.github.io/testblog/posts/some-sermon-ideas-on-spiritual-depth-pt1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 17:26:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://Spiritual-Entanglement.github.io/testblog/posts/some-sermon-ideas-on-spiritual-depth-pt1/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="some-sermon-ideas-on-spiritual-depth-pt-1"&gt;Some Sermon Ideas on Spiritual Depth pt 1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Related to Psalm 127&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God must lead the work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work done on our own, under our own willpower, will eventually fail. It will be shown to be ineffective and weak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To what can we compare the Kingdom of God? The individual is like an acre of farmland overgrown with weeds. Their soul is the ground. Their daily life is the fertilizer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="first-person"&gt;First person&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One person gets ready, takes some time off of work, and begins pulling weeds by hand; making use of all kinds of tools and implements. She or he works through the morning into the heat of the day. The work is boring and hard.&lt;/p&gt;</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="some-sermon-ideas-on-spiritual-depth-pt-1">Some Sermon Ideas on Spiritual Depth pt 1</h1>
<p>Related to Psalm 127</p>
<p>God must lead the work.</p>
<p>Work done on our own, under our own willpower, will eventually fail.  It will be shown to be ineffective and weak.</p>
<p>To what can we compare the Kingdom of God?  The individual is like an acre of farmland overgrown with weeds.  Their soul is the ground.  Their daily life is the fertilizer.</p>
<h2 id="first-person">First person</h2>
<p>One person gets ready, takes some time off of work, and begins pulling weeds by hand; making use of all kinds of tools and implements.  She or he works through the morning into the heat of the day.  The work is boring and hard.</p>
<p>Some weeds are uprooted easily, and quickly cast into the fire.</p>
<p>Other weeds are hard to pull, and not all the roots are extracted.  What is pulled is burned and destroyed, but the roots remain and quickly and easily begin to grow back.</p>
<p>Day after day the person must pull weeds, but always has to go over previously cleared ground to pull new weeds that have sprouted on that freshly turned ground. Or worse, they have to work again on old weeds, that still have roots deep in the ground.  Many days these old weeds stay under the surface, but eventually new growth breaks ground and begins to grow back stronger than ever.</p>
<p>After the days work, the person is so tired, they have to strength to invest is good fertilizer.  They settle for filling their mind with junk from all manner of convenient sources.</p>
<h2 id="another-person">Another person</h2>
<p>Another person sees the acre of weeds and is overwhelmed by the amount of work, and not knowing where to start.</p>
<p>After attempting to pull weeds, they eventually see the hopelessness of their efforts.</p>
<p>They begin to consult with the master gardener after the day&rsquo;s work instead of consuming endless entertainments.</p>
<p>The master gardener instructs them each night on where to plant good plants that can withstand the weeds.  He shows them how to attend to the plants each day, so they are properly fertilized and cared for.  Under his guidance the few plants grow strong and begin to crowd out the weeds around them.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Where Does Individual Responsibility Lie</title><link>https://Spiritual-Entanglement.github.io/testblog/posts/where-does-individual-responsibility-lie/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 13:47:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://Spiritual-Entanglement.github.io/testblog/posts/where-does-individual-responsibility-lie/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="where-does-individual-responsibility-lie"&gt;Where Does Individual Responsibility Lie&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been thinking a lot about how God can be so loving, and yet allow individuals to be condemned in the afterlife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since I started to draw near to God in prayer on a consistent basis, I have been able to see His hand in my life on so many levels. God&amp;rsquo;s movement in my life is so much clearer, and more sure then mere coincidence. But that is not the point of this entry. I mention it to atest that as I desire an ever-closer relationship with God, God responds and draws near to me. I just have to make the merest beginning of a step toward God, and He is right there already.&lt;/p&gt;</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="where-does-individual-responsibility-lie">Where Does Individual Responsibility Lie</h1>
<p>I have been thinking a lot about how God can be so loving, and yet allow individuals to be condemned in the afterlife.</p>
<p>Ever since I started to draw near to God in prayer on a consistent basis, I have been able to see His hand in my life on so many levels.  God&rsquo;s movement in my life is so much clearer, and more sure then mere coincidence.  But that is not the point of this entry.  I mention it to atest that as I desire an ever-closer relationship with God, God responds and draws near to me.  I just have to make the merest beginning of a step toward God, and He is right there already.</p>
<p>The more I demonstrate to God that I desire to be close to Him, and especially have my spirit and character formed by Him: to grow in Christ-likeness, to become more like Jesus, the more I find God helping me work on it.  And we are not working on everything at once, but working on a couple things at a time before moving on to something else.  I need to writ this out in another entry.</p>
<p>So what about people who never, or don&rsquo;t want, to think of God, even if they do so out of ignorance or misinformation?</p>
<p>Free will must come into play here.  If I show no interest in God, He will not force me.  But, I will be required to live with the consequence.  God will continue to give me opportunities to respond to Him: Wesley&rsquo;s idea of Prevenient Grace, which says that God is always calling or drawing us to Him.  The idea of Jesus standing and knocking on the door of our heart, but never forcing entry.  <em>WE</em> must be the one that opens the door and freely asks God to enter in.</p>
<p>I think many of the arguments around how much is enough have partially centered around this point: is just inviting God in the door enough?  Do it once, and you no longer have to worry about it?</p>
<p>I think many Christians expect that all formation and growth happen and are completed as soon as we invite God in.  They expect, specifically, that if you <strong>TRULY</strong> have invited God into your life/heart/spirit/whatever, then you will be immediately transformed into Christ-likeness, and you will be immediately free from all current sin, temptation, and have all the virtues and fruits-of-the-Spirit fully formed in you from that point until you die.  I have never met <em>anyone</em> seems to have had this happen in their life.</p>
<p>If <em>they</em> tell you it happened to them, then they need a humility check, and that is proof enough to me that they are misled.  Not condemned, not &ldquo;unsaved,&rdquo; but misled about how God effects growth and change in our heart and spirit, and therefore our outward expression of life.</p>
<p>So what about people that do not ever seem to want to have anything to do with God or Jesus or church, etc.?</p>
<p>Is that the point where God allows them to make their choice and they will face that decision when they die?</p>
<p>God did not write instructions for us to follow initially.  Adam was not created and handed the Bible.</p>
<p>I <strong>DO</strong> believe God has built into us (in our DNA? In our brains?) the desire to seek Him out in our lifetime.  But if we do not respond to that, are we condemned after this life is over.</p>
<p>If so, then that leaves the majority of humanity without God in the afterlife.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Second Post</title><link>https://Spiritual-Entanglement.github.io/testblog/posts/second-post/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 15:16:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://Spiritual-Entanglement.github.io/testblog/posts/second-post/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="heading-1"&gt;Heading 1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="heading-2"&gt;heading 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;more content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"&gt;&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"&gt;&lt;span class="line"&gt;&lt;span class="cl"&gt; &lt;span class="c1"&gt;#!/bin/bash&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="line"&gt;&lt;span class="cl"&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="line"&gt;&lt;span class="cl"&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;#34;foobar&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List 1
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sublist 1
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Item 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Item 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sublist 2
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Item 2.1
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is a test&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Item 2.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="heading-1">Heading 1</h1>
<p>Some content</p>
<h2 id="heading-2">heading 2</h2>
<p>more content</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span class="line"><span class="cl">   <span class="c1">#!/bin/bash</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">   <span class="nb">echo</span> <span class="s2">&#34;foobar&#34;</span>
</span></span></code></pre></div><ul>
<li>List 1
<ul>
<li>Sublist 1
<ul>
<li>Item 1</li>
<li>Item 2</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sublist 2
<ul>
<li>Item 2.1
<ul>
<li>This is a test</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Item 2.2</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>